A priceless true story.
The Duke is a comedy, drama, history film directed by Roger Michell.
In 1961, a 60-year-old taxi driver stole Goya’s portrait of the Duke
of Wellington from the National Gallery in London.
It was the first (and remains the only) theft in the Gallery’s history.
What happened next became the stuff of legend.
Kempton Bunton, played by Jim Broadbent.
Dorothy Bunton, played by Helen Mirren.
Jackie Bunton, played by Fionn Whitehead.
Mrs. Gowling, played by Anna Maxwell Martin.
Jeremy Hutchinson, played by Matthew Goode.
Kenny Bunton, played by Jack Bandeira.
The Duke is a 2020 British comedy drama film directed by Roger Michell,
with a screenplay by Richard Bean and Clive Coleman.
It is based on the true story of the 1961 theft of the Portrait
of the Duke of Wellington by Kempton Bunton.
The film stars Jim Broadbent, Helen Mirren, Fionn
Whitehead, Anna Maxwell Martin, and Matthew Goode.
It was Michell's penultimate film before his death on 22 September 2021.
The film was released in cinemas in the UK on 25
February 2022 to generally good reviews.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.